Guide to the George G. Gyrisco papers, [ca. 1940]-1984.
Gyrisco, George G. papers, [ca. 1940]-1984.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George G. Gyrisco papers, [ca. 1940]-1984.
21-23-2228
G. G. Gyrisco
26.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notes, reports, newsletters, photographs, and other files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files on graduate students and undergraduate advisees; general correspondence and subject files relating to entomology; research and conference notes and reports, files on insect control research and recommendations, and extension newsletters. Includes photographs of people and projects in Gyrisco's career.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of entomology, Cornell University.
George Gordon Gyrisco, born 1920, received his Ph.D from Cornell University in 1947.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files on graduate students and undergraduate advisees; general correspondence and subject files relating to entomology; research and conference notes and reports, files on insect control research and recommendations, and extension newsletters. Includes photographs of people and projects in Gyrisco's career.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gyrisco, G. G.; Palm, Charles; Schwardt, Herbert; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Graduate students.; Cornell University--Students.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Dept. of Entomology.
Subjects:
Entomology--Research.; Entomology--Study and teaching.; Entomology--Societies, etc.; Insect pests--Control.; Entomologists.; College teachers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Files of graduate students and undergraduate advisees (Box 10, 11, 12), and personal correspondence (Box 29) may be used and reproduced until 2030 only with the permission of the Head of the Department of Entomology at Cornell University.
CONTAINER LIST
- Commercial Correspondence, 1947-1984, A-P, filed by corporation, i.e., CIBA, DuPont, Hooker (Box 1)
- Same, S-Z; Grants-in-aid, A-Z, filed by corporation, i.e., Agway, Velsical; County Agents Correspondence, 1949-1959 (Box 2)
- Same, 1960-1983; Forage Crops Correspondence, Forage Insect Correspondence, 1958-1971; Extension Letters; Department of Entomology Letters; Personal Correspondence (Box 3)
- "Weekly Report on Insect, Diseases and Crop Development," 1967-1982 [unsorted]; "Cornell Fact Sheet: Chemical-Pesticide Program," 1965-1973 [unsorted] (Box 4)
- Jugatae Newsletter, 1949 -; Department Newsletter; TIEG Newsletter, 1971 -; "Comstock Comments," 1977-1978; "Weekly Reports on Insects ... to County Agents," 1964; "Cornell Fact Sheet: Chemicals-Pesticides Program," 1966; Computer Center Reports, University in Turmoil, 1968-1969; Comprehensive Review, Department of Entomology, 1973, 1979, 1984 (Box 5)
- Northeast Aerial Applicator's Conference, 18 vols., 1966-1983; NYS Insecticide and Fungicide Recommendations, 1978-1981 (Box 6)
- NYS Insecticide and Fungicide Recommendations, 1964, 1966, 1969, 1971-1976, [1955-1962, on microfilm in Mann Library]; Various college publications and material relative to NY agriculture (Box 7)
- [Eliminated by removal of duplicates during processing] (Box 8)
- Forage insects bibliography; Correspondence of Professor H.H. Schwardt, 1938-1946; European Chafer Reports, 1942-1954; Clover Root Borer Reports, 1937-1946; Seed Corn Maggot Reports, 1940-1949; Mexican Bean Beetle Reports, 1937-1944; General Forage Insects (Box 9)
- Graduate Student files, A-L [RESTRICTED] (Box 10)
- Graduate Student files, L-Z [RESTRICTED] (Box 11)
- Undergraduate advisees and general correspondence [RESTRICTED] (Box 12)
- Insecticide research reports, 1947-1963, Phyllophaga Reports and Data, 1936-1945, Alfalfa Snout Beetle Reports and Data, 1934-1947, Class notes and laboratory texts (Box 13)
- General correspondence, A-W, 1949-1981, Entomological Society of American, Extension (Box 14)
- USDA, College and Department committees files (Box 15)
- College and Department committee files (Box 16)
- University files, Laboratory requirements, Project statements (Box 17)
- Grant information NSF, NIH & CU, Insecticide residue research on milk, poultry, etc. (Box 18)
- Insecticide residue in milk, 1950s and 1960s, NE-36 reports, Birdsfoot trefoil experiments (Box 19)
- Insect control research and recommendations, NE-36 reports on pesticide residue in ... commodities, European chafer, Alfalfa snout beetle, photographs (Box 20)
- Forage crop program, Forage insect recommendations, Alfalfa Weevil (Box 21)
- Alfalfa weevil conferences, 1964-1974 (Box 22)
- Alfalfa weevil material including photos, Cereal leaf beetle projects, Department requirements for admissions, Grant proposals, Jugatae, Papers and lectures (Box 23)
- General files including teaching, research and professional information, 1940-1982, Manuscripts of articles, 1940-1982 (Box 24)
- Annual reports of forage insect infestation, 1948-1982, Multiple copies of 12th Annual Report, 1959, Retirement material, 1976-1977, Conference papers (Box 25)
- General files including teaching, community activity, correspondence, reports, 1973-1982 (Box 26)
- Photos: Riverhead, New York, 1943,1946; Near Bellville, New York, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Photos: Outside Comstock Hall, 1944; Insectory 1945, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Photos: George Gyrisco (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Photos: Near Malone, New York (releasing parasites), 1960 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Photos: Student/Staff, Cornell (individual), 1951-1959 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Photos: Student/Staff, Cornell (individual), 1959-1969 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Photos: Student/Staff, Cornell (individual), 1952-1976 (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Photos: Student/Staff (group), 1949-1971 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Photos: Other students (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Photos: Student/Staff, Massachusetts State University, 1940-1943 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  Includes photocopy portrait of Lotta Crabtree
- Photos: Professor Herbert Schwardt and Charles Palm (Box 27, Folder 11)
- Photos: Near Minetto lab, Oswego, New York (with Charles Palm?), 1935, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Photos: Student/Staff - collage of photos (Box 27, Folder 13)
- Papers on Comstock Hall history, forage crop history in entomology, and evolution/biblical thinking (Box 28)
- Personal correspondence, 1974-1983 [RESTRICTED] (Box 29)